JESSICA CHIU

FRONT-END SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

+1 236 978 4888 Jessica.Q.Chiu@gmail.com 1111 Seymour St, Vancouver www.jessicaqchiu.github.io

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Vancouver-based developer focused on accessible, responsive, and user-friendly software design who would love to join your team. Professional experience in a start-up environment with a proven ability to take initiative, prioritise tasks to meet deadlines, and write documentation. Pivoted from the finance industry as an analyst to become a self-taught developer.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front-end Development:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript. Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS. React, JSX, Next.js.

UX / UI Design and Project Management:

Wireframes, prototypes, usability testing, traditional art

Other: Agile, Scrum, Figma, Trello, Git, Github

Certificates/Online Courses:

Meta Front-End Developer Courses: Courses 1-6

Free Code Camp Certifications: Responsive Web Design, Front End Development Libraries, JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures

CORE SKILLS

- **Communication:** oral and written formal or specified.
- Adaptability: independent and collaborative work, takes initiative to learn new skills to provide additional support.
- Problem Solving: Proactive, motivated, and inquisitive keen to identify areas of improvement.

PROJECTS

- 2D platformer, ladybug jumper game HTML, CSS, Javascript (vanilla). Original hand-drawn art.
- Podcast landing webpage HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap, JQuery. Original art.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Operations Analyst - FNZ / Hatch, global wealth platform acquired investment start-up **2020 - 2022**

- **Developed improvements and solutions:** revised customer onboarding processes, banking and trading operations, and related communication. Designed and automated email campaign solutions to gather identification documents for verification.
- **Authored process documentation:** instrumental in training new employees, facilitating auditing and company acquisition, providing clarity around business operations, and streamlining team operations.
- **Managed tight deadlines:** handled reconciliation of FX revenue, completed daily control checks, and frequently liaised with the company broker to book time-critical FX trades.
- **Performed risk and compliance analysis:** reconciliation and verification of transactions, identified capital discrepancies, executed assurance checks.
- **Provided training and reviewed standards for AML/CFT regulations:** (CDD, KYC) responsible collection, evaluation, and use of sensitive data. Maintained records and issue logs to ensure processes were transparent to regulators and external auditors regarding breach and reconciliation recording.

Customer Support Specialist - Trade Me, New Zealand's leading e-commerce marketplace **2018 - 2020**

• Site functionality team. Experience identifying and communicating issues, processes, and solutions to users.

EDUCATION

(BCOM) Victoria University of Wellington

2017 - 2020

Bachelor of Commerce in Information Systems and Management, and specialisation in Information Technology Solutions.

Yoobee College of Creative Innovation 2016 Courses taken in web design, graphic design, game design.

Wellington Girls' College

2013 - 2016

Secondary school - NCEA all levels (1, 2, 3) acquired.

VOLUNTEER

Code Club Aotearoa & She Can Code

2018 - 2020